

Evanthia DIMARA evanthia.dimara@gmail.com www.evanthiadimara.com (+33) X XX XX XX XX

Evanthia Dimara

Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science

About me I am a Ph.D. candidate in the Aviz team, INRIA and University Paris-Saclay under the supervision of Pierre Dragicevic and Anastasia Bezerianos since October '14. My research field is **Human-Computer Interaction** and **Information Visualization**. I specialize in **decision making**: how to make it informed, conscious, unbiased and anticipating both for people who decide alone or in groups. I focus on the decisions for which the current DSS systems, models and people's heuristics tend to fail.

Education

2014 - 2017 (expected)

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Thesis (in progress): Decision making in information visualization

2012-2013

M.Sc. (Res): Research Specialty in Human Computer Interaction

Department of Sciences and Technologies for Information, Systems and Communication University of Paris-Saclay

March 2012

B.Sc. (4-year) in Computer Science

Department of Informatics and Telecommunications (DIT),

University of Athens, graduated with first class honors (GPA: 8.51/10)

Awards/Scholarships

- [1] Goverment Scholarship Award 2012 from University Paris-Sud, France
- [2] Scholarship Award 2012 from New York University Abu Dhabi
- [3] Scholarship Award 2006 from IKY2 bringing the highest score of all DIT candidates in National Exams. (19.181/20.000)

Experience

2014 - 2017 (expected): Researcher at AVIZ team, INRIA Saclay, France

project: The decision making in information visualization

<u>skills</u>: information visualization, human-computer interaction, literature review, research paper writing, crowdsource experiments, framework development for on-line experiments, statistical analysis, hypothesis generation, web technologies, cognitive biases, behavioral economics, marketing research

<u>tools</u>: D3, CakePhP, Javascript, Crowdflower, jQuery, Php, R, Photoshop, Illustrator, svn, Tableau, LaTeX

2013 - 2014: Research Engineer at AVIZ team, INRIA Saclay, France

project: Research infrastructure on digital archives for the medieval and World War 1 based on note-taking

<u>skills</u>: API front and back end development, faceted browsing, participatory design with historians and archivists, agile development, user testing

tools : Django, Python, git, Javascript, jQuery, rdf, ElasticSearch, PostgreSQL, Fabric, D3, extjs, RDFace

2013 - 2012: Research Intern at INSITU team, INRIA Saclay, France

project: Operant conditioning in Human Computer Interaction

skills: behavioral psychology, operant conditioning, ergonomics, motor and cognitive learning, user study, video encoding, touch typing tutor application, lightweight finger recognition model

tools : OpenCV, C++, QTcreator

Evanthia DIMARA

evanthia.dimara@gmail.com www.evanthiadimara.com (+33) X XX XX XX XX

2012 (summer): Visiting Research Assistant at Interactive Robotics and Media Laboratory, New York University Abu Dhabi (NYU), Arabic Emirates

project: Towards an empathizing and adaptive storyteller system

skills : user study, conversational agent, emotion tracking, storytelling,

narrative, adaptive emotion tagging, human-robot interaction

tools : Greta, FaceAPI, SHORE engine

2011 (3 month): Research Intern at REVES team, INRIA Sophia-Antipolis, France

<u>project</u>: Design and implementation of an immersive virtual reality environment for interaction through natural gestures.

<u>skills</u>: user experience design, 3D programming, experiment design, gesture interaction design and implementation, virtual reality, physics engine, WAND interaction

tools: OpenSceneGraph (OSG), CAVE, Bullet, OsgBullet, OsgVR library, VRPN, ART tracking (Flystick, FingerTracking, Head-tracker), Gina library

2009 - 2011: Network Administrator at Network Operation Center, Athens

<u>skills</u>: troubleshooting for university services (email, ftp, vpn etc), client technical support

tools: cisco Switches (Catalyst 5000, 6000, 3550)

2010

digitization of secondary education books for the Greek Ministry of Education

Skills

Research Skills

o problem solving o analytical skills o multidisciplinary research o state of the art review of experiment design of evaluation methods of crowdsource experiments of participatory design of user studies of interviews of article writing of public speaking of prototyping of statistical analysis

Technical Skills

Web technologies

o D3 o CakePHP o HMTL o jQuery o AngularJS o Node.js o Django

Programming Languages

 \circ Javascript \circ C \circ C++ \circ Php \circ R \circ Java \circ Python \circ Prolog \circ Bash Script \circ Android SDK \circ LaTeX

Operating Systems

o Linux o Macintosh o Windows

Language Skills

Greek (native) and English (fluent)

Ph.D. Additional Training

Behavioral Economics and Psychology: 63 hours, July 2015

BEHAVE Summer school, Schola Empirica in Prague

<u>skills</u>: decision making beyond computer science, international and multidisciplinary networking with senior and junior researchers, state-of-art of behavioral economics/finance and experimental psychology, workshops on experimental methods, policy making, practical applications of organizational management

Evanthia DIMARA evanthia.dimara@gmail.com www.evanthiadimara.com (+33) X XX XX XX XX **Law and intellectual property**: 18 hours, February - March 2016 skills : knowledge on the context of industrial and academic research and innovation, contract law, intellectual property law, author rights, industrial property, patents and trademarks

Digital Fabrication: 20 hours, October 2016 (EXPECTED)
FABLAB DIGISCOPE, Digiteo Labs, Gif-sur-Yvette, France
skills: 3D-printing, digital fabrication, hardware design and fabrication for novel interaction devices and physical visualizations